Sercan Hocaoğlu

Software Engineer

Istanbul, Turkey+905344302959

in linkedin.com/in/sercan-hocaoglu/

Summary

I am a passionate highly enthusiastic Software Engineer with 4+ years experience actively involving with the latest technology and updates in the software development field, have been working in the development teams with agile methodology at large organizations.

I mostly design, build and develop backend web applications, APIs, backend services in large-scale and highly available distributed systems. I'm also interest and ability to learn other programming languages and technologies.

I have strong desire for knowledge and new challenges. I'm passion for innovation and learning. I am a fast learner who picks up new software skills quickly, team player, well-organized, self-educated, self-motivated and versatile person.

Skills

Programming Languages: Java, Python, C/C++, JavaScript

Web Technologies & Frameworks: REST, SOAP, Spring, Spring Boot, HTML, CSS, Vue.js

Distributed Systems & Devops: Docker, Kubernetes, OpenShift, RabbitMQ, Apache Kafka, Logstash, New Relic, Grafana

Data Management: PostgreSQL, Oracle, Couchbase, Cassandra, Redis, Elasticsearch

Strong Knowledge: Distributed Systems, CI/CD, OOP, Design Patterns, Algorithms & Data Structures, Agile, Scrum, TDD, Git, Maven, Jenkins, Linux

Work experience

Sr. Software Engineer

11/2019 - Current

ING, Istanbul, Turkey

- Participate in a platform development team which has a team size of 8 members, work with agile methodologies and provides architectural, infrastructural, internal solutions, tools, platforms and integrating external platforms to the existing system.
- · Work collaboratively with an architectural team to discuss, plan and execute on microservice transformation project
- · Responsible for;
 - · Developing an internal framework, tools and building REST APIs with Java,
 - Managing CI/CD and scaling microservices via OpenShift which is a platform based on Kubernetes and Docker,
 - · Redesigning existing banking services with microservice patterns and approaches

Tech stacks: Java, JavaScript, Spring Boot, REST, Docker, Kubernetes, OpenShift, RabbitMQ, Apache Kafka, Grafana, ElasticSearch, Logstash, Kibana, Cassandra, CI/CD, Agile, Scrum, Microservices, Banking

Software Engineer 11/2018 - 11/2019

Trendyol Group, Istanbul, Turkey

- Worked in part of an agile software development team of the e-commerce web site which has 25M+ actively users
- · Designed and developed REST APIs by using Java with Spring Boot and an UI by using Javascript with Vue.js
- Managed and scaled 40M+ products with high throughput in the distributed system by providing low latency, fault tolerant and high availability.
- Delivered and operated large-scale, highly available distributed system with the microservice deployment patterns using Kubernetes with Docker

Tech stacks: Java, JavaScript, Spring Boot, REST, Docker, Kubernetes, Microservices, CI/CD, TDD, Agile, Scrum, RabbitMQ, Couchbase, PostgreSQL, Graylog, New Relic, ElasticSearch, Pair programming, E-commerce

Software Engineer 11/2016 - 11/2018

Yapı Kredi Bank, İstanbul, Türkey

- Participated in the software development team of the payment system of the bank which has 20M+ customers
- Developed and implemented Java applications, web services, core banking business processes of payment methods with involving in all phases of the SDLC
- Maintained and optimized critical finance datas with high availability and strong consistency

Tech stacks: Java, J2EE, Spring, SOAP, REST, Hibernate, SOA, Oracle, PL/SQL, Payment System, Banking

Education